(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-14T22:52:13.389705",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
1st generation 電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言
1st Generation Cyber Pure Oshi Declaration
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！
[Hololive 1st Gen 7th Anniversary!]
月夜のセレナーデ
Serenade of the moonlit night
白い薔薇は誰を想う
Whom does the white rose think of?
その身を匂わせて
Exuding its fragrance,
愛を歌うの
it sings of love.
こぼれ落ちた花びらが
The fallen petals
寂しさの跡を隠した
hid the traces of loneliness.
ねぇ早く迎えに来て
Hey, come get me quickly,
最後の一片が落ちるその前に
before the very last petal falls.
今はどんな花とも群れないの
Right now, I won't flock with any other flower,
あなただけを待ってる
waiting only for you.
あなたとならこの体が
If it's with you, even if this body
壊されたっても構わない
is destroyed, I don't care.
棘に触れたら傷つくわ
If you touch the thorns, you'll get hurt,
その覚悟がないなら
if you don't have that resolve,
いっそここから消えてよ
you might as well disappear from here.
重く閉ざした Secret Garden
Heavily locked away Secret Garden.
夜風はリゾルート
The night wind is resolute,
白い薔薇は覚醒する
the white rose awakens.
射貫かれるように
As if shot through,
扉開いた
the door opened.
ただ一人で枯れてゆくの？
Will I wither away all alone?
待ってるだけじゃいられない
I can't just keep waiting.
衝動の赴くまま
Driven by impulse,
茨の道を裸足で駆け抜けてく
running barefoot down a path of thorns.
凛と咲き誇る花でありたい
I want to be a flower blooming with dignity,
あなただけを求めて
seeking only you,
会いに行くのどんな遠く
going to meet you no matter how far,
離れていても見つけ出せる
finding you even if we're apart.
暗い世界も怖くない
Even a dark world isn't scary,
あなたを感じるから
because I can feel you.
すべて失ったっていい
Even if I lose everything, it's okay,
二度と戻らない Secret Garden
never turning back from Secret Garden.
今はどんな花とも群れないの
Right now, I won't flock with any other flower,
あなただけを求めて
seeking only you.
霞の向こう私を呼ぶ
Calling me beyond the mist,
鮮やかに燃える強気な薔薇
a bold rose burning brightly.
凛と咲き誇る花でありたい
I want to be a flower blooming with dignity,
やっとここで出会えた
finally having met here.
あなたとならこの体が
If it's with you, even if this body
壊されたっても構わない
is destroyed, I don't care.
棘に触れたら傷つくわ
If you touch the thorns, you'll get hurt,
その覚悟があるのね
but you have that resolve, don't you?
手を取り合えば広がってく
Holding hands, it expands before us—
誰も知らない Sacred Universe
a Sacred Universe that no one knows.
はーい！お疲れ様でしたー！
All right! Great job, everyone!
1期生ライブスタート！
1st Generation Live, start!
さてじゃあちょっとね Secret Garden 歌った後なんですけども
Now then, right after singing "Secret Garden"...
まずは自己紹介！7年目の自己紹介！
First, self-introductions! For our 7th year!
やっていきますか！じゃあアキロゼから！
Shall we get started? Let's begin with AkiRose!
はーい！7年目の自己紹介いきます！
Yay! Here comes my 7th-year self-introduction!
ホロライブ1期生、癒し系ハーフエルフのアキロゼこと
From Hololive 1st Generation, the soothing half-elf,
アキ・ローゼンタールです！
Aki Rosenthal!
ハロハロハロ〜 アローナ〜！
Haro haro haro~ Aloha~!
そして！白上フブキでーす！お願いしまーす！
And next, I'm Shirakami Fubuki! Nice to meet you!
いつもシンプル...
Always simple...
あれ？どこ行ったんだ？
Huh? Where did it go?
レギュラーになった
It became a regular bit!
なんかさ、心の...ごぼう抜き？
Like, pulling out the roots of your heart...
やめてくれ！やめてくれ！
Stop it! Stop it!
みんながいる中でさ、最近普通に自己紹介するの恥ずかしくなっちゃって...
Lately, doing a normal self-introduction in front of everyone makes me feel so embarrassed...
みんなで初手恥捨てよう！
Let's all cast away our shame first!
いや、無理無理無理！じゃあ、そんな恥を捨てたはーちゃま！
No, no way, no way! Okay then, let me introduce Haachama who has cast away her shame!
見せてあげるよ！はーちゃま、ちゃま～！ワールドアイドル、最強アイドル、はーちゃまこと赤井はーとです！
I'll show you! Haachama, chama~! The world's strongest idol, Haachama, Akai Haato-desu!
推し推し推し推し！
Oshi, oshi, oshi, oshi!
じゃあ続いて！
Okay, next up!
はい！ホロライブの清楚担当、みんなのアイドル、夏色まつりです！
Yes! Hololive's pure and cheerful idol, everyone's idol, Natsuiro Matsuri-desu!
清楚！7年目も清楚でやっていくで～！
Pure! I'll keep being pure into my 7th year~!
ちょっと聞こえない... でも、まじ清楚か？
I can't really hear you... But are you really pure?
最近ね、最近だいぶ落ち着きを取り戻し...
Lately, you know, lately I've really regained my calm...
はい！ということでね、1曲目『Secret Garden』だったんですが...
Alright! So, our first song was "Secret Garden"...
去年の周年で発表したオリ曲ということで、あれから1年経ちました！
That was our original song announced at last year's anniversary, and one year has passed since then!
早い～！あの告知からもう1年！
So fast~! It's already been a year since that announcement!
いや、早いね！あっという間！秒！
Yeah, so fast! In the blink of an eye! Just seconds!
本当、秒すぎる～！
Seriously, it felt like seconds~!
はい、今回はね、オープニングとして歌わせていただきましたけど、今年はオリ曲どうなんですか、はーとちゃん？
Yes, we sang that as our opening today, but what about an original song for this year, Haato-chan?
えっ、どう...どうなるんだろうね？
Eh... what will happen, I wonder?
どうなのかな～？
How will it be~?
さあ！そしてそして、なにやらステージが...見てくださいよ！
Now then! And look at the stage... check this out!
すご～い！じゃじゃ～ん！
Amazing~! Ta-da~!
どこだここ～？今回のステージはなんと、バーチャル世界の秋葉をイメージして...
Where is this~? This stage was designed with the image of virtual Akiba in mind...
VTuberならではのね、デジタル感とか、あとは推し活感？
...giving it that VTuber-esque digital feel, and maybe a fan culture vibe?
雰囲気もあって...
It's got that atmosphere...
ちょっとYAGOやめて？一番眩しいんだけど！1号店、2号店あるし！
Wait, stop with the YAGO billboards! That's the brightest thing here! There's Store 1 and Store 2!
もう、もろジャメカよ！
Man, it's straight-up Jameka!
みんなのね、結構色々な思い出の、なんていうの？物語が...
Everyone's memories and... what do you call it? Stories...
色々な所に散りばめられてるんだよね！
...are scattered around all over the place!
ね！とっても格好良くて可愛らしいイメージとなっておりますので、そちらも是非楽しんでください！
Right! It's got a really cool yet cute image, so please enjoy that as well!
そしてさらに！今回のハッシュタグは...こちら！
And what's more! Today's hashtag is... this!
デデン！#電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言 ！
Tada! #DennoPureOshiDaisengen !
感想いっぱいXでポストしてくれるよね？
You'll post lots of your impressions on X, right?
ちなみに、このハッシュタグですが、なんでこの名前かは最後まで見てくれたらその秘密がわかっちゃうかもしれません！
By the way, as for this hashtag, if you watch until the end, you might find out the secret behind why it's named this way!
えっ、本当？分からなかった場合はどうしたらいいですか？
Eh, really? What should we do if we can't figure it out?
はーちゃまが責任を取るよ！
Haachama will take responsibility!
責任を取る？何でもする！
Take responsibility? She'll do anything!
ということでですね、この格好可愛いステージにみんな勢揃いして、色々歌っていきたいんですけども...
So then, with all of us gathered on this cool and cute stage, we want to sing various songs, but...
まずはですね、ソロパートからやっていこうと思います！
...first off, we're going to start with the solo parts!
さてさて、ソロの順番もあらかじめ発表しちゃいますか？
Now then, shall we announce the order of the solo performances in advance?
1曲目歌う人！
Who's singing the first song!
はい！まつりちゃん！
Me! Matsuri-chan!
まつりちゃんのソロはどんな感じなんですか？
What kind of song is Matsuri-chan's solo?
この雰囲気に合った曲を選んだので楽しみにしてください！
I picked a song that fits this atmosphere, so please look forward to it!
なるほどなるほど。じゃあそしてその次は？
I see, I see. And then, who's next?
はい！はーちゃまは、モリモリで行きましたのでお楽しみに！新しい曲もある！
Yes! Haachama went all out with tons of energy, so look forward to it! There's even a new song!
おお～！そしてその次が？
Ooh~! And after that?
はい！アキロゼです！
Yes! Aki Rosenthal!
どんな感じの曲ですか？
What kind of song is it?
この空間にぴったりで、ワイドで新世界みたいな、地球みたいなでっかい感じでいかせていただきます！
It fits this space perfectly—grand, like a new world, a big scale like the Earth!
なるほどなるほど！
I see, I see!
最後は白上なんですけど、自分の好きな楽曲を歌わせていただく予定でございますし、なにやら騒がしい予感がしますのでお楽しみに！
And last is Shirakami! I plan to sing my favorite song, and I have a feeling it's going to get quite lively, so look forward to it!
ということで、トップバッターとしてまつりちゃんいかせていただきますよ！それではいきましょう、どうぞ！
So then, as the top batter, Matsuri-chan is going to kick things off! Here we go, go ahead!
UNHAPPY?
悩める人の子よ
Oh, troubled child of man
UNLUCKY?
人ならざる者も
And non-human beings as well
BE HAPPY!
抱きまず目指せよ
Embrace it and aim for it
生きていんだし
Since you're alive
目を逸らした過去も
The past you looked away from
大層な未来も
And the grand future too
カウンセリング やれやれ
Counseling, oh dear
ここらで一回 PEACE PEACE
Let's take a break here, PEACE PEACE
UNHAPPY?
UNLUCKY?
BE HAPPY!
ARE YOU READY?
ねえねえねえねえ 何だ動揺して
Hey hey hey hey, why are you flustered?
戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
I feel like I'm fighting, or something like that.
触れられない 触れ難くもない
Untouchable, yet not hard to touch either.
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分と
Confronting my past self, my self, my self...
もうとうに死んでる
...with a transparent phantom...
透明な亡霊と対決
...that died long ago.
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
Deep within childish, painful memories.
残念？ もういないのに
Too bad? Even though it's already gone.
あれ？ そっちが良い？ アイロニーね
Huh? You prefer that one? How ironic.
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is the one being seen through my current self?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, an indelible label.
Yes! 要はコンプレックス
Yes! In short, it's a complex.
取り憑かれているみたい
It's like I'm possessed.
巻き付いたまま
Coiled around me...
まだ離れない
...it still won't let go.
在りし日の自分
The self from days gone by.
死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
It's not dead—a chain of you and yourself.
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
Living means continuing to change.
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't settle for misfortune and be satisfied.
幸せになろうとしないで選んで
Don't just try to be happy, choose it.
この世は奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world is a bizarre, strange fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
Who knows what demon or serpent will appear next?
出会ってやっと始まる物語
A story that only starts once we meet.
さあ人が化け物が
Come, whether human or monster...
ピース ピース
Peace peace
Future
can't change the Past
Past & Future
run for the Future
カットイン!
Cut in!
何がどうして未来になんぞ
Why and how can I expect...
何の希望も期待出来来ない
...nothing in terms of hope or expectation for the future...
ような気がして
...or so it feels...
もう随分生きてる
...having lived for so long.
既視感とテンプレで食傷
Sick of déjà vu and boilerplate formulas.
素敵な出来事の気配もない
No sign of anything wonderful happening.
残念
What a shame.
積んだ経験の因果 骸骨化された神話
Karma of accumulated experience, a skeletonized myth.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
In short, I just want excitement.
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
"I'm bored, I got used to it."
なんて
...saying things like that.
整っていくガイダンス
Tidy guidance...
増えるコンプライアンス
...increasing compliance...
塞がれていくみたい
...it feels like I'm being boxed in.
吸い尽くして
Sucking it all dry...
あれもこれもどれも
That, this, and everything else...
同じ味がする
...all taste the same.
死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
You're not dead—a chain of you and yourself.
いつつの世も過去も未来も現在にあるんだ
Every era, past and future, exists in the present.
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Honestly fulfill the act of living.
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending!
お前はお前に言ってるんだ
You're saying this to yourself.
幸せを諦めてしまうな
Don't give up on happiness!
人であれ
Remain human.
ただ苦しみに慣れて
Just getting used to pain...
耐えているだけじゃ
...and enduring it...
死んでいるのと同義
...is synonymous with being dead.
屍のアンデッド
A corpse of an undead.
UNHAPPY?
UNLUCKY?
言い訳ばかり集めさせて
Making you collect nothing but excuses...
生きているんだろ
...that's how you're living, right?
不幸に浸るのも
Soaking in unhappiness...
幸せになるのも
...or becoming happy...
全部全部お前だ
...it's all, all on you.
古今東西
All times and places,
一切合切
all and everything,
森羅万象
all creation.
清く 正しく 美しく
Purely, correctly, beautifully,
8年目からは、キレイな赤井はあとに戻ることを
starting from my 8th year, returning to a clean Akai Haato...
私は
...I...
誓います！
...solemnly swear!
な〜んて言うと思った？
...As if I'd ever say that!
1期生のみんな！7周年まで1人も欠けずに、止まんねぇよなぁ！YES!
1st gen everyone! 7th anniversary without missing a single member, we ain't stopping! YES!
Good god! I just wanna live honestly
雑音ばかり
Nothing but noise.
That's alright I'm gonna go my way
Every time I stay white
静観してなよ 優等生は
Just stand by and watch, honor student.
Fake up 正義の味方
Fake up, ally of justice.
(It's true of world)
Isn't it?
You must (Please, Please, Please)
Do as I told (Please, Please)
I'm sick of hearing (Just for yourself, for yourself) words
I ain't so good girl (Freeze, Freeze, Freeze)
Never be lap dog
「正論」的なのもういいって
Enough with the "righteous arguments."
「物語に必要」と
"Necessary for the story," you say?
そこまで言うのなら
If you're gonna go that far...
演じ切ってやるわ
...I'll play the part to the end!
いい子ちゃんのまま
Remaining a good little girl...
Yes, yes, yes, No, No, No, No
Who is the Villain?
だって I'm a Hero, right? right? right?
After all, I'm a Hero, right? right? right?
イヤになるわ
I'm getting sick of this.
誰が正義なんて
Who decided what justice...
決めたのかしらね
...is anyway, I wonder?
Oh well
(Who? ×5)
もう どっちだって
Whichever it is...
そう いい子ちゃんのままじゃ
...if I just stay a good little girl...
はいっ ちゃんちゃん！
...that's all folks!
Yeah
Who is the Villain?
1, 2, 3, Go!
I give you my big RED HEART
My my big RED HEART, My my big RED HEART
I'll be true to my RED HEART
my my big RED HEART, my my big RED HEART
I give you my big RED HEART
My my RED HEART, big RED HEART
I'll be true to my RED HEART
my my big RED HEART, my my big RED HEART
いっただっきまーす♡
Bon appétit!
めちゃゴミ♡完♡全♡食!!
Super Garbage Complete Meal!!
トントカトン！ トントカトン！
Chop chop chop! Chop chop chop!
お肉と野菜をトントカトン☆
Chop chop meat and veggies☆
ザクリンパっ！
Slice and dice!
カラピッチュ！←揚げ物だって出来ちゃいます！
Crisp-fried! (You can even make fried food!)
ぐとぐと
Simmering away
タラリンチュラリン エビのアジ！
Drizzled with flavor, shrimp taste!
はあちゃまクッキング
Haachama Cooking
は〜じまっちゃま〜〜！
Is starting now~~!
1. 調べない
1. Don't look things up
調べたやつからザクリンパ！
Slice up anyone who looks things up!
ネットやレシピを見るのは
Looking at recipes online is...
ダメダメ！
A big no-no!
2. 測らない
2. Don't measure
測るのはゴミ！
Measuring is trash!
目分量でも作れるのが一流行だろぉおお！
Real top-tier chefs eyeball everything!
3. はちゃめちゃアレンジ！
3. Wild, crazy twists!
最後にオリジナルの隠し味！
Finally, a secret original ingredient!
これが料理の成長物語...！
This is a tale of culinary growth...!
はあちゃまカレーは5つ星☆☆☆☆☆
Haachama Curry gets 5 stars ☆☆☆☆☆
スパイスマシマシで！
Extra spice, please!
作り方を今教えます。
I'll teach you how to make it now.
めんどくさいので省きます！
It's too annoying, so I'll skip it!
（てめえで勝手に作れ）
(Make it yourself, damn it)
見た目はゴミでもめちゃ美味しい
Looks like trash, but tastes amazing
目指すは世界一ー！
Aiming to be number one in the world!
あなたの胃袋掴んじゃう
I'm gonna grab your stomach
ぎゅっ ぎゅっ ぎゅっ ぎゅっ はい、あーん♡
Squeeze squeeze squeeze squeeze, say ahhn♡
友達減る 見せたら減る
You lose friends, show them and you lose friends
左から2番目に醤油！
Soy sauce in the second from the left!
正気で美味しい完♡全♡食
Truly delicious complete meal
お残しした人だあれ？
Who left food behind?
BAN！
BAN!
おつるーじゅ！
Otsu-ruuju!
It's only love
もしも願い一つだけ
If I had only one wish
叶うなら
that could come true,
君のそばで眠らせて
let me sleep by your side,
どんな場所でもいいよ
no matter where that place is.
Beautiful world
迷わず君だけを見つめている
Without hesitation, I gaze only at you
Beautiful boy
自分の美しさ まだ知らないの
You don't yet know your own beauty
It's only love
寝ても覚めても
Whether asleep or awake,
少年マンガ 夢見てばっか
I do nothing but dream of shonen manga.
自分が好きじゃないの
Don't you like yourself?
何が欲しいか分からなくて
Not knowing what I want,
ただ欲しがって
I just keep wanting,
ぬるい涙が頬を伝う
and lukewarm tears trickle down my cheeks.
言いたいことない
I have nothing to say,
ただもう一度会いたい
I just want to see you once more.
言いたいこと言えない
I can't say what I want to say,
根性なしかもしれない
maybe I'm just a coward.
それでいいけど
Even so, that's fine,
もしも願い一つだけ
but if I had only one wish
叶うなら
that could come true,
君のそばで眠らせて
let me sleep by your side,
どんな場所でもいいよ
no matter where that place is.
Beautiful world
迷わず君だけを見つめている
Without hesitation, I gaze only at you
Beautiful boy
自分の美しさ まだ知らないの
You don't yet know your own beauty
It's only love
どんなことでもやってみて 損したって
Whatever you try, even if you lose out,
少し経験値上がる
you gain a little bit of experience.
新聞いらない
I don't need newspapers,
大事なことが載ってない
the important things aren't printed in them.
最近調子どうだい？
How have you been feeling lately?
元気にしてるなら
If you're doing well,
それでいいけど
then that's fine,
僕の世界消えるまで
but until my world vanishes,
会えるなら
if we can meet,
君のそばで眠らせて
let me sleep by your side,
どんな場所でもいいよ
no matter where that place is.
Beautiful world
儚く過ぎて行く日々の中で
In these days passing fleetingly by,
Beautiful boy
自分の連れなさ まだ知らないの
you don't yet know your own coldness.
星に願いひとつだけ
Only one wish upon a star
どうか私 貴方の傍で眠らせて
Please let me sleep by your side
All quartets lead, lead to...? Say la-la-la...
やあ また会えたね
Hey, we meet again!
こんばんは いや こんにちはだっけ
Good evening, or was it good afternoon?
広いようで 狭いようで
It seems wide, yet narrow...
退屈は要らないみたいだね
Looks like boredom isn't needed here!
ああ 問題は依然あって 頭痛いんだけど
Ah, problems still remain, giving me a headache, but...
少しずつって言い聞かせて 願い事叶えて行きましょうね
Telling myself "step by step", let's fulfill our wishes!
(I shall remember, I wanna do, I shall remember)
拾い集めた後悔のかけらたちを
The fragments of regret I gathered...
夜が明ける前に ラベルを貼って並べてって 希望に変える準備を継続中
Before night breaks, labeling and lining them up, preparing to turn them into hope!
桜が咲いて散ったその後で
After the cherry blossoms bloom and scatter,
何が真実なのかはわかるから future melody
I'll know what is true, future melody,
そう 今は奏でて あいよ 世界救うだなんて 僕は信じてないけどね
So play it now! Sure, I don't believe in saving the world or whatever,
今 目の前の君が 明日を生きれるくらいには
But enough for you right in front of me to live through tomorrow,
ありえない不条理はぶっ飛ばしていけ
Blow away all impossible absurdities!
余計な必要ないよ 嘘つき
No need for unnecessary things, liar!
さあ アンプリファーは絶好調 エレキギターがうねってる
Now the amplifier is in top shape, the electric guitar is roaring!
こんなにも歪んでるのに 心が純粋に求めてる
Even though it's so distorted, my heart purely craves it!
ああ 何回も何千回もお望み通り鳴らすよ
Ah, time and time again, thousands of times, I'll sound it just as desired!
君が欲しいタイミングでわがままにスイッチを押しましょうさ
At the timing you want, let's selfishly press the switch!
(you can reaction, and play it loud, you can reaction)
(you can react, and play it loud, you can react)
はしゃぎ過ぎてた青春時代のいろはとか
The ABCs of our youth when we were fooling around too much,
ホコリ被る前に 選びだして磨いてって 歌に乗っちゃう番狂わせしたい
Before they gather dust, pick them out, polish them, I want to pull off an upset riding this song!
一斉のせで魔法も使えるよ 君は自由なんだから
On three, we can even use magic, because you are free!
止めないで future symphony そう お気に召すまま
Don't stop the future symphony, yes, just as you like!
不器用でも混ぜ合わせるよ この街に響いていけ
Even if clumsy, I'll blend it together, go echo through this city!
ミュージック 歪なるミュージック 大丈夫 僕らが試金石
Music, distorted music, it's fine, we are the touchstone!
ジャジャジャジャーン 足りない！ キック、リズムを打て！ ベース＆ギター おまけに僕が歌えば四重奏
Ta-da! Not enough! Kick, hit the rhythm! Bass & guitar, plus if I sing, it's a quartet!
(I shall remember I wanna do, I shall remember I wanna do)
忘れない 忘れないよ 今も大人になっても
I won't forget, I won't forget, even now as I grow up,
だからこの瞬間は楽しませて
So let me enjoy this moment!
歌うよ でたら目でいいよね？
I'll sing! Nonsense is fine, right?
All quartets lead, lead to...? Say la-la-la...
桜が 桜が
The cherry blossoms, the cherry blossoms
咲いて散ったそのあとで
after blooming and falling,
何が真実なのかはわかるから
I'll know what the truth is, so
future melody
そう 今は奏でて
Yes, play it right now.
愛が世界救うだなんて僕は信じてないけどね
I don't believe that love saves the world, though.
今 目の前の君が明日を生きられるくらいには
Just enough for you right in front of me to live tomorrow,
ありえない不条理はぶっ蹴飛ばしていけ
kick away the impossible absurdities!
with 喜怒哀楽 余すな全部惜しみもなく
With all your emotions, leave nothing behind without holding back!
言えないまま飲み込むなんて事はよしにして
Stop swallowing your words without speaking them!
with 喜怒哀楽 大丈夫さ どこまでも行くだろう
With all your emotions, it's fine, we can go anywhere!
All quartets lead, lead to...? Say la-la-la...
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
よっしゃー！ということでソロパートでしたー！
Alright! So that was my solo section!
あれ？みんな、あれ、お着替えしてたの？一緒に今。
Wait, did you guys change your outfits just now? Together?
何何その動き、何その動き、怖っ！
What's with those movements? Creepy!
え、大丈夫？どうしたみんな？なんからどこ行ってたの？ちゃんと見てくれてた？
Wait, are you okay? What happened? Where were you? Were you watching me properly?
ずっと一緒にいたよ！
We were together the whole time!
嘘！いたの？
Lies! You were here?
一番近くで見てた！
We were watching from the front row!
えー、そうだったの？
Oh, is that so?
なんか確かにちょっと今日多いなとか思ってたけど…
I did think there were a lot of people today, though...
はーい！ということでですね、ソロパートだったんですけども、じゃあちょっと一人ずつね、改めて感想などなどなんですが…
Alright! That was the solo part, but let's go over our impressions one by one...
まつりちゃんのアンデット…
Matsuri-chan's "Undead"...
はい！アンデットね、やっぱこの雰囲気に合わせて選んだんですけど、なんかこの歌詞が、すごいMVっぽく出してもらってね。
Yes! I chose "Undead" to match this vibe, and the lyrics displayed like a real MV!
そうなんですよ。かっこ可愛く歌えたかなと思います。
That's right! I hope I sang it cool yet cute!
そしてハーハーちゃん！
And next is Ha-ha-chan!
イエーイ！ハーハーと一緒に踊りましたー！
Yay! I danced together with Ha-ha!
そして新しく出たね、メチャゴミ完全職、みんなどうだったー？
And how did everyone like the newly released standard version?
ねー！
Right!
そしてアキちゃん！
And Aki-chan!
はーい！アキロゼは…
Yes! AkiRose...
いや、結構頑張らせてもらったんだけど…
Well, I really worked hard on it...
この空間でね、こういう演出をね、ずっとずっとやりたいなって思ってたから、ちょうどね、世界観にも合ってるし、すごく頑張りました！
I've always wanted to do this kind of production in a space like this, so it fit the world view perfectly, and I worked really hard!
さすがだったよー！
You were amazing!
はい！最後はね、フブキは一匹だったんですけど、なんかスコンプがやたら多かったんですけど…
Yes! Finally, Fubuki was alone, but there were somehow a lot of Skonbu...
一緒にですね、白髪バンド曲がすごく大好きなのね、こちらの「桜のあと」歌わせていただきました！
Since I really love white-haired band songs, I sang "Sakura no Ato"!
本当にありがとうございます！めちゃめちゃ楽しかったです！
Thank you so much! It was so much fun!
はい！そしてここからは？
Okay! And from here on out?
ここからは、それぞれが1期生のイメージに合う楽曲を1曲チョイスして全員で歌うプロデュース楽曲パートです！
From here, each of us picked a song that fits the 1st generation image for everyone to sing together!
みんなどんな曲選んだのか、めちゃめちゃ楽しみですね！
I'm super excited to see what songs everyone picked!
まつりはね、王道かなっていう曲を選んだんですけど…
Matsuri chose a song that feels like a classic...
ちゃまはどんな曲？
What kind of song did Chama choose?
ちゃまは、可愛くて仲良しな曲にしました！
Chama picked a cute and friendly song!
アキロゼはね、今時感もありつつ、ちょっとダークな一面もあるんじゃないかなみたいなね。
AkiRose's song has a modern vibe while showing a bit of a dark side.
フブキちゃんは？
What about Fubuki-chan?
白髪はですね、1期生だからこそ沁みる曲！
Shirakami chose a song that hits home precisely because we are 1st Gen!
ということでですね、皆さんもコメント欄などで予想して楽しみに！
So everyone, please predict in the comments and look forward to it!
それではグループパート、せーの、スタート！
Ready, set, start the group part!
好き嫌いかの人間論 どちらかと言えば好きでした
A human theory of likes and dislikes; if anything, I liked it.
乗りかかった船止ちゃうほど 落ちぶれていないよ わかるでしょ
I haven't fallen so low as to abandon a ship I boarded, you know?
障害物も結構ある こちら取られるすぎ人生観
There are plenty of obstacles; a worldview that gets easily overwhelmed.
行き先なんて二の次なんです 聴こえてるでしょ
The destination comes second; you can hear me, right?
アクセルしか踏まないよ
I'll only step on the accelerator
止まり方なんて必要ない
There's no need to know how to stop
涙もエンターテインメントになる カメラ止めないで
Even tears turn into entertainment, don't stop the camera
ハイ、チーズ！
Say cheese!
不甲斐ない私でもずっと歩いてきた道がある
Even as clumsy as I am, there's a path I've walked all this way
つまりどうでもいいことなど何もなかったんだよ
In short, there was nothing that didn't matter
私混乱上々
I'm high on chaos
いつだって現場が最前線さ
The front line is always right here
最後まで目を離さないで
Don't take your eyes off until the very end
そりゃ私だって悩みのひとつやふたつはありますよ
Well, even I have a worry or two, you know
眠れない夜の数々
Many sleepless nights
選択肢のスタンピード
A stampede of choices
バックアップなんてしたくないよ
I don't want to make backups
オートセーブ切って挑むからリアルなんだ
I turn off auto-save to take it on, that's why it's real
緊張を脈動に変えるわがままですみませんっ！
Sorry for being selfish and turning tension into a pulse!
変わんない私だからきっと繋いできた夢がある
Because I never change, there's surely a dream I've connected
つまりどうでもいいことなど何もなかったんだよ
In short, there was nothing that didn't matter
私逆境上々
I thrive on adversity
いつだって現在が最高潮さ
The present moment is always the climax
最後まで手を離さないで
Don't let go of my hand until the end
最後まで私負けないから
Because I won't lose until the very end
出会った日の閃きも 偽りも
The spark from the day we met, and even the lies
憧れも 止めな 止めるなよ
The longing too—don't stop, don't stop it!
から回ったエネルギー 輝くこのステージで
The energy that ran wild, shining on this stage
覚醒する物語 瞬きすんなよ
A story awakening, don't you dare blink!
シタイから！ シタイとき！ シタイでしょ！？ いっしょに！
Want to! When you want to! You want to, right?! Together!
あたしたちはここにいます！
We are here!
ここには夢がちゃんとある
There are dreams right here
フレンドなら 友達でしょ
If we're friends, we're pals, right?
「すき」って言ってみた (「だいすき！」)
I tried saying "I like you" ("I love you!")
放課後なら 当たり前のこと
After school, it's totally normal
さあさ集まれ こっそり帰るな
Come on, gather up, don't sneak home!
部活動だよ 活動しちゃうね
It's club activity, let's get active!
遊んでるんじゃないの ありませんっ！
We're not just playing around!
ただいま ってあの子が言うよ (「おかえりー」)
"I'm home," that child says ("Welcome back!")
みんなでいれば大丈夫 (「ぶー！」)
If we're all together, we'll be fine ("Boo!")
エビバディ セイ！ 友達でいよーね
Everybody say! Let's stay friends!
シタイから！ シタイとき！ シタイでしょ！？ だいすき！
Want to! When you want to! You want to, right?! Love you!
あたしたちは楽しんでる！
We are having fun!
24時間はしゃいでる
Fooling around 24 hours a day
屋上に真っ赤な太陽
A crimson sun above the rooftop
かなり叫んでみた (「元気でーす！」)
We shouted pretty loudly ("We're feeling great!")
あたしたちはここにいます！
We are here!
ここには夢がちゃんとある
There are dreams right here
フレンドなら 友達でしょ
If we're friends, we're pals, right?
「すき」って言ってみた (「だいすき！」)
I tried saying "I like you" ("I love you!")
キーンコーンカーンコーン からの下校タイム
Chime rings, then it's time to head home
いいえ わたしたち まだ帰らない (「やだよー」)
No, we're not going home yet ("No way!")
部活動だよ 活躍しちゃうよ
It's club activity, we're gonna shine!
新入部員 募集チュッ！
Recruiting new club members!
ごめんね って小さく言うよ
Saying "I'm sorry" softly
ケンカするほどほにゃららら？
The more you fight, the closer you get?
ネバギバ！ 最強になれるね
Never give up! We can become the strongest
シタイから！ シタイとき！ シタイでしょ！？ いっしょに！
Want to! When you want to! You want to, right?! Together!
あたしたちは経験する！
We are gaining experience!
食べて眠って賢くなる
Eating, sleeping, getting smarter
校庭に涼風吹いて
Cool breeze blowing across the schoolyard
大きく手を振る (「また明日ねー！」)
Waving big hands ("See you tomorrow!")
あたしたちはここにいます！
We are here!
ここには夢がちゃんとある
There are dreams right here
フレンドなら 友達でしょう
If we're friends, then we're good pals, right?
「好き」って言ってみた
I tried saying, "I like you!"
みんながここに集まれば
When everyone gathers right here,
学校は特別になる
school becomes somewhere special.
今日が終わっても明日も
Even when today ends, tomorrow too,
笑顔で会えるね!
we can meet with a smile!
あたしたちはここにいます!
We are right here!
ここには夢がちゃんとある
There's definitely a dream right here.
フレンドなら 友達でしょう
If we're friends, then we're good pals, right?
だいすき ありがとう!
I love you so much, thank you!
どうしてすぐ知ってしまうの
Why do I figure it out so quickly?
共振で苦しんで狼狽
Suffering and flustered by resonance,
Q.更新で降る闇石抹消可？
Q: Can dark blocks falling in updates be erased?
悪くない？
Is it not bad?
興味ねぇ救い 派手感動
Uninterested in salvation, flashy emotion,
常備ねぇ薬 食べ BAD
No emergency medicine, eating it turns BAD,
Q.超酷えフル見た目暗号化？
Q: Super terrible full visual encryption?
金による1号化？
Monetized into Number 1?
常識ねぇ狂いっぱなしで乱調
Unconventional, constantly wild and out of sync,
放置ゲーする陰キャラでバンド
An introverted band playing an idle game,
Q.送信で苦しいダメ Cancel は？
Q: Is "Cancel" painful when sending?
草生えるcel は？
What about "lol"-inducing cel?
どうしてすぐ見てしまうの
Why do I look right away?
どうしてすぐ言ってしまうの
Why do I speak right away?
どうしてすぐ見てしまうの
Why do I look right away?
どうしてすぐ壊れちゃうかな
Why does it break so easily?
(パパラ)
(Pa-pa-ra)
近未来しか勝たん
Near future is the best,
ショッピングモールの現代コンピュー
modern computer in a shopping mall,
小窓 死とか加担
Small window, complicit in death,
モンティホールの経費でピンボール
Pinball on the Monty Hall expense account,
オイルマッ
Oil mas—
オイルマッサージ100分コース 足湯付き
100-minute oil massage course with foot bath,
柚子を添えて
garnished with yuzu.
テテテテトテトテテテテテトリス
Te-te-te-te-to-te-to-te-te-te-te-Tetris!
どうしてこんな目に に に
Why am I going through this, this, this?
興味がないこと本気じゃないもの全部後回しで
Putting off everything I'm not interested in or not serious about,
知ってることは知らんぷり 私は終わってる
feigning ignorance about things I know, I'm completely hopeless.
恥ずかしい過去知ってる奴らの記憶消させて
Let me erase the memories of those who know my embarrassing past,
迷惑かけてごめんってば ねぇ誰か助けて
I said I'm sorry for being a hassle, hey, someone help me!
狂信ですぐ引かれちゃうの
Getting turned off by fanaticism,
(タタラタタラタラ)
(Ta-ta-ra-ta-ta-ra-ta-ra)
もう見ねぇ すぐ引かれ SAD
Not looking anymore, instantly turned off, SAD,
常軌で狂いたて MAD
Diverging from sanity, MAD,
行きたくない 行きたくない 生きたくない
Don't wanna go, don't wanna go, don't wanna live,
ばーいばい
Bye-bye!
臨時休業 洗濯ボール
Temporarily closed, laundry pod,
ナイチンゲールの配信ゲーム
Nightingale's game stream,
名刺交換の名シーン
Famous scene of business card exchange,
借金ボウルでチンチロハイボール
Cee-lo highball in a debt bowl,
温泉旅行3泊4日食事付き
Hot spring trip, 3 nights 4 days with meals included,
早く行きてぇ
I wanna go so bad!
テテテテトテトテテテテテトリス
Te-te-te-te-to-te-to-te-te-te-te-Tetris!
共感性羞恥 恥 恥
Secondhand embarrassment, shame, shame,
鬱とかそーとか忙しくて眠れないわ今日も
Too busy with depression and mania, I can't sleep today either,
誰か早く殴って気絶させてくれよ
Someone hurry and punch me unconscious!
人生キャンセルキャンセル界隈ぼんやりとした不安
Life cancel-cancel crowd, a vague anxiety,
私のせい 私が悪いよそうだよ
It's my fault, I'm the bad one, that's right.
興味が出ても本気でやっても全部空回りーで
Even if I get interested or try hard, it all goes in vain,
知らないくせに嘘つき 私は終わってる
A liar despite knowing nothing, I'm completely hopeless.
恥ずかしい過去知ってる奴らの記憶消させて
Let me erase the memories of those who know my embarrassing past,
迷惑かけてごめんってば ねぇ誰か助けて
I said I'm sorry for being a hassle, hey, someone help me!
迷惑かけてごめんってば ねぇ誰か許して
I said I'm sorry for being a hassle, hey, someone forgive me!
絶対 アイドル辞めないで
Never quit being an idol,
ずっと 輝いてる君を見たい
I want to see you shining forever.
もう ずっと ずっと ずっと ステージにいて
Stay on stage forever, forever, forever!
私があの君の床 離れたなら
If I ever were to leave your side,
君はちょっと寂しくなるかな
would you get a little lonely?
いじわる 考える
Thinking mean thoughts...
好きな人がいるのなら 内緒にして ねぇ
If you have someone you like, keep it a secret, okay?
ねぇ 神様は将来と指輪を どこかに隠してね
Hey, God, please hide your future and wedding ring somewhere.
君の「好き」に合わせたんだ 髪の色
I matched my hair color to what you like.
私の中 君だけで 過剰摂取は中毒へ
Only you inside me, overdose leads to addiction,
責任とってね 大好きです
Take responsibility, okay? I love you!
せーの!
Ready, go!
絶対 アイドル辞めないで
Never quit being an idol,
優しい目も 真面目顔も
Your gentle eyes, your serious face...
全て知ってる私が言う！
I, who know everything about you, say it!
絶対 空で輝いて
You must shine up in the sky...
星は街じゃ輝かないの
Stars don't shine down in the city.
眩しい君が世界一だよ
Dazzling you, you're the best in the world!
君の夢は何ですか？教えてほしい
What is your dream? I want you to tell me.
その夢がアイドルじゃなくても 覚悟してるから
Even if that dream isn't being an idol, I'm prepared for it.
星のいない空 それが当たり前で
A sky without stars, that was just normal...
暗い道に目が慣れずに 踏み出すのも怖かった
Unaccustomed to dark paths, I was scared to step forward.
そんな時やっと見えた光
That was when I finally saw the light.
絶対 君は歌ってて
You must keep singing...
ただのエゴと分かってても キラキラ衣装が似合う
Even if I know it's pure selfishness, sparkly outfits suit you best.
絶対 大きなステージで
Surely, on a massive stage...
一列でも前で感じたい
I want to feel it even one row closer to the front.
今日の歌い方 なんか好きだな
The way you sing today, I kinda love it.
君の努力 私の愛 成り立つ頃が崩壊
Your effort, my love—right when it comes together, it crumbles.
脆いの 星の幸せを願った
It's so fragile... I wished for a star's happiness.
だけど でもね だって君はアイドルよ ずっと
But still, you know, because you're an idol, forever.
初めて目が合った日から
Ever since the day our eyes first met,
今日も明日も君ばかりだ
today and tomorrow, it's all about you.
絶対 アイドル辞めないで
Never ever quit being an idol!
これは報われないおとぎ話 恋よりももっと好きだ
This is an unrequited fairy tale, I love you even more than romance.
魔法よどうか 解けないままで
Magic, please, stay unbroken forever.
イェーイ！
Yeah!
はい！ということで...
Alright! So...
プロデュース曲パートでした！
That was our self-produced song section!
どうだったかなー？
How was it, everyone?
ということで、じゃあちょっと...
So then, let me talk a bit...
選曲、1曲目はまず『Q』でございました！
For the setlist, first up was "Q"!
いや、めちゃくちゃいい曲なのに、めっちゃ激しいダンスだったと思うんですけども！
Man, it's such a great song, but the dance was super intense!
いやもう、なんか本当にこの曲聴いて、絶対1期生これだろっていう...
I mean, hearing this song, I really felt "This has gotta be 1st Gen!"
ねー、思いながらちょっと歌分けとかもね、させていただいたんですけども...
Yeah, while thinking that, I also helped divide up the vocals...
初めて聴いて染みた！
Listening to it for the first time really hit home!
染みるでしょ！そう！染みたーい！
It hits home, right?! Yeah! So touching!
そう！我々は常に最前線ということで！
That's right! Because we're always on the front lines!
やったー！1期生これからも頑張っていこう！最後まで目を離すんじゃないぞ！
Yay! 1st Gen, let's keep working hard! Don't take your eyes off us till the end!
離さないー！目を離すなよー！
We won't! Don't look away!
そして、そして次が...
And then, next up...
はい！アキ・ローゼンタールの『アストリス』を選ばせていただきました！
Yes! I picked Aki Rosenthal's "Astris"!
いや、これはね、可愛かったから、いつかみんなでやってみたいなと思ってたの！
Yeah, it was so cute, I've always wanted to try performing it with everyone!
で、グループの結構フォーメーションとかをゴロゴロした...
And the group formations were all over the place...
そう、それをね、ちょっと頑張ってもらっちゃった！
So I had everyone work really hard on that!
ありがとう！みんな頑張ってくれて！
Thank you! Thanks for working so hard, everyone!
みんな表情やばかった！めっちゃ笑顔だったけどね！
Everyone's facial expressions were wild! Super smiley though!
我々はだいぶムスッとした... まあ、そんな一面も愛してよっていうことで！
We looked pretty stern at times... Well, please love that side of us too!
はい！お願いします！そして？
Yes! Please do! And next?
はい！そしてはーちゃまは『フレンドしたい』！
Yes! And Haachama picked "Friend Shitai"!
フレンド！したかったー！
I wanted to be friends!
フレンドじゃなかったの？！ということで選びました！
We weren't friends before?! So that's why I picked it!
あの、後ろの映像でね、思い出アルバム...
You know, in the video behind us, the memory album...
気づいた？みんな！よかった！盛り倒されてなくてよかった！
Did everyone notice? Thank goodness it didn't get buried!
まだ割れてないです！
It hasn't broken yet!
はい！そして！
Yes! And next!
まつり最後に『絶対アイドル辞めないで』！
Lastly, Matsuri chose "Zettai Idol Yamenaide"!
いや、これはね、まつりのエゴだったとしても、みんなにはアイドルで一番あってほしいなという気持ちで選ばせていただきましたよ！
Even if it's just my ego, I chose it wishing for everyone to remain the ultimate idols!
この曲もなんか1期生でやると、やっぱ染みたね！
Performing this song with 1st Gen really hit home too!
確かにね！分かる！やっぱ7年目だから...
Truly! I get it! After all, it's our 7th year...
すごく良かったです
It was really great!
お、そして、このパートが終わったということは？
Oh, and since this part has ended, what does that mean?
じゃあそろそろ、ハッシュタグの秘密を教えちゃうかな？
Then maybe it's about time to reveal the secret of the hashtag?
なんと、このハッシュタグなんですが、新曲のタイトルになってます！
Surprisingly, this hashtag is actually... the title of our new song!
ということはタイトルは...「電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言」？
So that means the title is... "Dennou Pure Oshi Dai Sengen"?
えー！これ一体どんな曲なんだ？
Ehh! What kind of song is this going to be?
一体どんな感じなんだろう？
I wonder what it feels like?
楽しみ！
Looking forward to it!
いや、ドキドキでございますけれども、「ぴゅあ推し大宣言」ってことは、なんかあれ、みんなの曲ってことかな？ファンのみんなの曲？
Yeah, I'm so excited, but "Pure Oshi Dai Sengen"... does that mean, like, it's everyone's song? A song for all the fans?
あー！そういうことか！推してくれてるよな！
Ah! Is that it? "You're supporting us, right?"
推してくれてるよな！っていう曲なのか？
A song that goes, "You're supporting us, right?"!
そう！みんながね、この配信見てくれてるみんなが、わたしたちのこと、推し...だよね？
Right! Everyone who's watching this stream... we're your oshi... right?
え？
Huh?
まさか、他の人によそ見なんかしてないよね...？
You're not, like, looking at anyone else, right...?
四六時中、わたしたちのこと、考えてるよね...？
You're thinking about us 24/7, right...?
えー、一期生が推しだって、宣言してくれるよなー！？
Hey, you'll declare that 1st Gen is your oshi, right?!
ということで、それでは聴いてください！一期生の新曲、せーの、「電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言」！
And with that, please listen! 1st Generation's new song, ready, set... "Dennou Pure Oshi Dai Sengen"!
は〜い、これから配信始めるよ
Hii, we're starting the stream now!
みんな見てる〜？
Is everyone watching~?
今回はコラボ配信！
This time it's a collab stream!
あれ？あれれ〜？ コメントの熱量、なんだかくなくない？？
Huh? Huh~? Isn't the energy in the comments a bit low??
まだまだ足りない！こんなの...
Still not enough! Not like this...
のお〜〜〜〜〜〜〜ん！！！
NOOOOOOOO!!!
このこのこのこの！
This, this, this, this!
推し変は許しませんっ！！！
Changing your oshi is not allowed!!!
「わ・た・し」だけに尽くしてね♡
"De-vo-te" yourself only to me♡
わたしだけにひと筋
Solely devoted only to me
単推しじゃなきゃヤダヤダ　拗ねちゃうぞ
If I'm not your solo oshi, no way no way, I'll sulk!
他の子にちょちょちょっとでも　よそ見をしたらプンプンめっ！
If you look at other girls even a little bit, I'll be so mad at you!
めらめらメンヘラップ
Fiery menhera rap
ほっぺふくら　にらめっこしましょ
Puffing cheeks, let's have a staring contest
あっぷっぷ　ぷいっ！！
Ready, set... hmph!!
フクレ顔のが可愛いでしょ！
A sulking face is cuter, right?
目移りはダメ！ほんとイヤイヤ
Looking away is bad! I really hate it
いつも観て観て　わたし待ってる
Always watch me, watch me, I'm waiting
あなたが推してくれる愛ちゃんの全部が...
All of the affection you give to support me...
わたしをささえる栄養素♡
is the nutrients that sustain me♡
〔LOVE YOU（らぶゆ）〕×5　（四六時中夢中）
〔LOVE YOU〕x5 (Infatuated 24/7)
ねえ　とってもとってもとってもとっても愛してほしい
Hey, I want you to love me so, so, so, so much
〔HAPPY（はっぴ）〕×3　ぎゅっ（最上級　はぴゅ）
〔HAPPY〕x3 Hug (Top-tier Happu)
ほら　やっぱりやっぱりやっぱりやっぱり　はっきりはっきりはっきりはっきり
See, as expected, as expected, clearly, clearly
〔推して推して〕
〔Support me, support me〕
わかったでしょ？〔ピュアピュアに　振りきって〕　ぴこぴこ　キモチのバロメーターも超アガる
Got it, right? 〔Go full-on pure-pure〕 Piko-piko, my feeling barometer is skyrocketing
〔単推し〕〔神推し〕〔愛おしい〕
〔Solo oshi〕 〔Godly oshi〕 〔Adorable〕
もうほんとにほんとにほんとにほんとに　わかってね！！！
Really, really, really, really understand, okay???
お〜い、みんなー！ここまでついて来れてる？
He~y, everyone! Can you keep up so far?
このあともこの調子で行くよー！！！
We're gonna keep this momentum going, okay?!
うりゃおい　うりゃおい　うりゃおい　うりゃおい
Urya oi! Urya oi! Urya oi! Urya oi!
ちょ待って、なんで他の子褒めるの？
Wait a sec, why are you praising other girls?
〔よそ見疑惑発令中〕
〔Looking-away suspicion alert engaged〕
わたし以外も気になってるでしょ！
You're interested in someone other than me, aren't you?!
〔ありえないよ　ありえない〕
〔Unbelievable, unbelievable〕
他の子にちょちょちょっとだけ　よそ見したよね！？ うそマジ無理です
You looked at other girls even just a little bit, didn't you?! No way, seriously I can't
ピュア推し信者　わたし推さんじゃ？
Pure oshi believer, aren't you gonna support me?
指切りしてよ　ハリセンボン×1000
Make a pinky promise, 1,000 fan blows!
心変わりしたらほんとに
If you change your mind, seriously
拗ねる、怒る、泣いちゃうからね...
I'll sulk, get mad, and cry...
推し変はしてないね
You haven't changed your oshi, right?
「わ・た・し」だけに尽くしてる！！！
"De-vo-ting" only to me!!!
だってほら　コメントが愛に溢れている♡
Look, after all, the comments are overflowing with love♡
瀕死のHP　みるみる回復♡♡
Dying HP recovering in no time♡♡
チート級レベルな　栄養補給♡♡♡（パワーチャージ）
Cheat-tier level nutrient supply♡♡♡ (Power charge)
ごめごめごめちょ　ごめごめごめちょ
Sorry, sorry, super sorry! Sorry, sorry, super sorry!
〔LOVE YOU（らぶゆ）〕×5　（四六時中夢中）
〔LOVE YOU〕x5 (Infatuated 24/7)
ねえ　いっぱいいっぱいいっぱいいっぱい愛してほしい
Hey, I want you to love me so, so, so, so much
〔HAPPY（はっぴ）〕×3　ぎゅっ（最上級　はぴゅ）
〔HAPPY〕x3 Hug (Top-tier Happu)
もう　うっとりうっとりうっとりうっとり　にっこりにっこりにっこりにっこり
Now, enchanted, enchanted, smiling, smiling
〔推して推して〕
〔Support me, support me〕
わたしの為　日々、日々、推しごと〔ピュアピュアに　ひたむきに〕　励んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for working hard on your oshi duties for my sake, day by day 〔Purely, single-mindedly〕
〔単推し〕〔神推し〕〔愛おしい〕
〔Solo oshi〕 〔Godly oshi〕 〔Adorable〕
ぜったいぜったいぜったいぜったい　ぜったいぜったいぜったいぜったい！
Definitely, definitely, definitely, definitely! Definitely, definitely, definitely, definitely!
お願いね！！！
I'm begging you!!!
このこのこのこの〜〜〜！！
This, this, this, this~~~!!
銀河の...まで愛して☆（ほしい）
Love me... all the way to the galaxy☆ (Please)
ということで、新曲でしたー！
And that was our new song!
めっちゃ可愛い曲だったね！めちゃめちゃ可愛いし、なんかね、「推し」って感じで！
It was such a cute song! Super duper cute, and felt so "oshi"-like!
ねー！みんなにもね、ぜひ歌ったり踊ったりね、いっぱい楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいなという一曲になってるんだけど、どうだったー？
Right~! It's a song where we'd be so happy if everyone enjoyed singing, dancing, and having fun with it, so how was it~?
いや、もうやっぱ楽しいね、この曲ね！超ド級の白上のど趣味な曲！
Yeah, it really is fun, this song! A ultra-tier song totally right up Shirakami's alley!
この曲聴いたときに
When I listened to this song,
あ、これこれ。ちょっとまつりちゃん...
"Ah, this is it! Matsuri-chan..."
にね、ちょっと頑張ってもらおうかなっていうところで、セリフのところとかちょっとねまつりちゃんに...
"...I thought we should have Matsuri-chan try her best with the spoken lines and stuff."
そう、歌詞分けをフブキがね...
Yeah, Fubuki did the lyric distribution!
そうそうそう！書いてくれたんですよね。
That's right! She wrote it out for us.
ちょっとキメっぽいところはまつりちゃんかなと思って今回ね。
I thought Matsuri-chan would fit the cool, dramatic parts this time.
あそこみんなよく噛まなかった！偉い！
Everyone managed to say it without tripping over their words! Great job!
偉かったよー！
We did great!
あとアキロゼセクシーだったね！
Also, AkiRose was so sexy!
お尻叩いてた！めちゃ可愛かった！
Slapping her butt! That was so cute!
まつりちゃんに銃で撃たれてたとき...
When Matsuri-chan was shot with a gun...
バン！バン！
Bang! Bang!
あれ可愛かったねー！めちゃ可愛かった！
That was so cute! Super cute!
ほい！そんなこの曲が？この曲が？なんと！
Alright! So this song... this song is... what?!
お？なんと？！ 21時15分から...
Ooh? What?! Starting at 21:15...
こちらの公式チャンネルで...
...on this official channel...
先ほど歌わせていただきました新曲「電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言」の...
...the MV for our new song "Denno Pure Oshi Dai Sengen" that we just performed...
MVが出ちゃいます！
...will be released!
めちゃめちゃ可愛い映像になってますので、ぜひそちらもチェックしてくださいね！
It turned out to be such a cute video, so please make sure to check it out!
さて！ではここからは告知タイムです！
Now then! From here on, it's announcement time!
今回のグッズは！「hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade」！
This time's merch is... "hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade"!
こちら5月30日からカートオープンされてまーす！
Cart orders have been open since May 30th!
はい！みなさんチェックしてくれてると思いますが...
Yes! I'm sure you've all checked it out already, but...
内容見てみましょうー！
...let's take a look at the contents!
はい！まずキービジュアルはオットン先生に書いていただきました！
First, the key visual was drawn by Otton-sensei!
今年のホロ全体での期生周年グッズのテーマは「パレード」！
This year's overall Hololive generation anniversary merch theme is "Parade"!
その中でも我々1期生は「マーチング隊」でーす！
And among them, we 1st Gen are the "Marching Band"!
ではでは1個ずつグッズ見ていきましょうかね！こちら！
Now then, shall we look at each piece of merch one by one? Here!
はい！まずはですね、プレミアムアクリル色紙！
Yes! First off, the Premium Acrylic Artboard!
きゃわちい！
So cute!
こちら複製サインとロゴが箔押しで入ってます！
This comes with a foil-stamped duplicated signature and logo!
そして続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
オフィシャルホロカスリーブ Anniversary Parade 1期生バージョン！
Official Holoca Sleeve: Anniversary Parade 1st Gen Version!
ホロカが入ります！カードもスリーブも1期生で揃えてあげてください！
Holoca cards fit right in! Please pair your cards and sleeves with 1st Gen!
そして次はこちら！じゃん！
And next is this! Tada!
はい！アクリルスタンドー！
Yes! Acrylic Stands!
今回のキービジュアルの衣装がアクリルスタンドになりましたよー！
The outfit from this key visual is now available as acrylic stands!
なんとプレミアムアクリル色紙に比べてそれぞれ表情が異なっちゃいますよ！
Amazingly, compared to the Premium Acrylic Artboard, each character has a different facial expression!
集めたくなっちゃうね！
It makes you want to collect them all!
そして最後はアキロゼー！
And lastly, AkiRose!
はい！なんと記念メダル出ちゃいます！
Yes! Surprisingly, commemorative medals are coming out!
こちらなんとケースと巾着がついて豪華な仕様になっておりまして！
These actually come with a case and a drawstring pouch for a luxurious specification!
期生ごとにね、デザインが異なっているので...
The design differs for each generation...
ぜひぜひコレクションしたくなっちゃうアイテムなんじゃないのかなと思っています！
...so I think it's an item that will definitely make you want to collect them all!
タレントカラーとのお名前も入っているのでぜひゲットしてね！
It also includes the talent's color and name, so please get yours!
そしてこちらのグッズなんですが、受注期間がえーっと...
And as for these goods, the pre-order period is, let me see...
5月30日金曜日から今月6月30日...
...from Friday, May 30th to June 30th of this month...
月曜日までなのでみなさん忘れずにご予約してくだい！
...until Monday, so everyone please don't forget to order yours!
以上！周年のグッズ告知でしたー！
That's all for the anniversary merch announcement!
そして！なんとまだある！
And! Surprisingly, there's even more!
次はメンバー個別のお告知タイムです！
Next is the individual member announcement time!
一つずつね！まつりちゃんから！
One by one! Starting with Matsuri-chan!
はい！じゃあまつりは周年グッズの告知にしますよー！
Yes! Then Matsuri will announce her anniversary goods!
はい！ということで、このあとですね、21時30分から...
Yes! So after this, starting at 21:30...
まつりの個人の周年グッズが出ちゃいますので...
...Matsuri's individual anniversary goods will be released...
ぜひぜひ買ってください！超可愛いイラストです！
...so please buy them! The illustrations are super cute!
そしてはあちゃーん！
And next is Haachama!
はい！はあちゃまはこちら！ドドン！
Yes! Haachama's is right here! Ta-da!
めちゃゴミ♡完♡全♡食!!
Mecha Gomi Kan-Zen Shoku!!
本日の0時から各種配信サービスでも配信されるのでお楽しみに！
It will also be available on various streaming services starting at midnight tonight, so look forward to it!
6周年グッズもあリまーす！明日ですよー！
6th anniversary goods are also available! They're coming tomorrow!
あ、間違えた！7周年グッズも！
Ah, I made a mistake! 7th anniversary goods as well!
お楽しみに！
Look forward to it!
はい！白上です！
Yes! Shirakami here!
白上もですね、グッズが出るんですけども、こちらはですね、6月3日に発売予定でございます！
Shirakami is also releasing merch, and it's scheduled to go on sale on June 3rd!
グッズの詳細などは、よければ6月3日の配信をお楽しみに！
For details on the merch, please look forward to the stream on June 3rd!
はい、そして最後、アキちゃん！
All right, and lastly, Aki-chan!
はいはいはいはい！アキロゼの、なんと！
Yes, yes, yes, yes! Aki Rosenthal's, surprisingly...
2024かな？自分の生誕祭の時にお披露目しました
In 2024, was it? Revealed during my birthday stream,
ミュージカル『ブレーメン』の曲が、ついに発売になりました！
the songs from the musical "Bremen" are finally released!
やったー！
Yay!
なります！この後24時リリース予定なので
They are! They're scheduled to release tonight at midnight,
ぜひいっぱい聴いたり、歌ってみたり踊ってみたりして楽しんでもらえたらなと思っています！
so I hope you listen to them a lot, sing along, dance, and enjoy them!
あと、ミュージックビデオとしてね、そのミュージカル部分だけ切り取ったものも上げようと思っているので
Also, I'm planning to upload just the musical parts as music videos,
アキロゼのチャンネルもぜひ見てください！
so please check out Aki Rosenthal's channel too!
はい！以上、告知タイムでした！
All right! That was the end of the announcement time!
ワーイ！
Yay!
ということでですね、7周年を迎えて...
So with that, as we celebrate our 7th anniversary...
えっ？8周年ですか？明日から
Wait? Is it our 8th anniversary starting tomorrow?
あれ？本当だ！
Huh? That's true!
ということは、ちびっこに例えると、中...中学2年生！
So, to put it in terms of kids, 2nd... 2nd year of middle school!
我々は中2だ！中学2年生！
We're 2nd year middle schoolers! 8th graders!
中2になった！
We became 8th graders!
封印が解けるようだ！これ以上解き放たれたらまずい！
It feels like the seal is breaking! It'd be bad if we released any more!
爆発しちゃうよ～！
We'll explode!
まあね、これからもスローペースでやっていく1期生でございますけれども
Well, we 1st generation members will keep going at a slow pace,
これからも楽しく活動していきますので、皆様よろしくお願いします！
and we'll continue to enjoy our activities, so please support us!
よろしくお願いします！
Please support us!
頑張ろうぜ！頑張ろうぜ！
Let's do our best! Let's do our best!
はい、それではですね、またそれぞれの配信でお会いしましょう！
All right, then, let's meet again in our respective streams!
せーの！
Ready, set...
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
Game over.